Guide to the John N. Warfield papers, 1931-2009
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: Audiovisual Materials, 1978-2000; (21 boxes)
  - "Center for Interactive Management (C.I.M) Influences Seminar: Dr. John N. Warfield", November 1986 (Box 61, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Moving Towards a Consensus for Nursing in Virginia," (IASIS) George Mason University, 1986 (Box 61, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking toward the 21st Century," [Tape 1 of 5], May 16, 1988 (Box 61, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking toward the 21st Century," [Tape 2 of 5], May 16, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking toward the 21st Century," [Tape 3 of 5], May 16, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking toward the 21st Century," [Tape 4 of 5], Mary 17, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking toward the 21st Century," [Tape 5 of 5], May 17, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Moving Towards a Consensus for Nursing in Virginia," (IASIS) George Mason University, 1986 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking Toward the 21st Century," [Tape 1 of 5], May 15, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking Toward the 21st Century," [Tape 2 of 5], May 6, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking Toward the 21st Century," [Tape 3 of 5], May 16, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking Toward the 21st Century," [Tape 4 of 5], May 17, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Forum on the Future of Pediatric Nursing: Looking Toward the 21st Century," [Tape 5 of 5], May 17, 1988 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture, Class Lecture #9," George Mason University [Tape 1 of 1], March 27, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture, Class Lecture #11," George Mason University [Tape 1 of 2], April 17, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester CLass Lecture, Class Lecture #11," George Mason University [Tape 2 of 2], April 17, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture, Class Lecture #12," Guest Lecturer Dr. Benjamin Broome Talks About his work with Interactive Management, George Mason University [Tape 1 of 2], April 24, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture, Class Lecture #12," Guest Lecturer Dr. Benjamin Broome talks about his work with Interactive Management, George Mason University [TAPE 2 OF 2], April 24, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture #13," George Mason University., May 1, 1999 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture #14," George Mason University [Tape 1 of 1], May 8 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Managing the Unmanageable Process Leadership in Organizations" [John N. Warfield][Tape 1 of 1], February 23, 2000 (Box 62, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "John N. Warfield Spring Semester Class Lecture, Class Lecture #14," George Mason University [Tape 1 OF 1], May 8, 1999 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Managing the Unmanageable,Process,Leadership in Organizations" [John N. Warfield][Tape 1 OF 1], February 23, 2000 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#6], November 6, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S),"[#7], November 7, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#8], November 7, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#9], November 7, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#10], November 7, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#11], November 8, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#12], November 8, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S),"Unedited, November 8, 1985 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#1], January 13, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#1], January 14, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#2], January 14, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#3], January 14, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#1,#2], January 15, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#2], January 16, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," [#3], January 16, 1986 (Box 63, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 1 OF 12], June 5, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 2 OF 12], June 5, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 3 OF 12], June 5, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 4 OF 12], June 5, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 5 OF 12], June 6, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 6 OF 12], June 6, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 7 OF 12], June 6, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 8 OF 12], June 8, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 9 OF 12], June 6, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 10 OF 12], June 7, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 11 OF 12], June 8, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation Workshop " [Tape 12 OF 12], June 8, 1989 (Box 64, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Center for Interactive Management: Quality Design," [Tape 1 of 1], 1989 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Center for Interactive Management, University Forum: Sociotechnical Disasters," [Tape 1 of 1], 1989 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Dr. F. Ross Janes in a Classroom Discussion of Interactive Management, Monterey, Mexico," [Tape 1 of 1], April 1996 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Interactive Management Workshop," [Stan Crognale][Two Copies], 1992 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Designing a Computer Science Curriculum for the 21st Century," National Science Foundation Workshop, 1987 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Curriculum Workshop: Mathematics for Computer Science," First Day [Tape 1 of 5], November 10, 1986 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Curriculum Workshop: Mathematics for Computer Science," First Day [Tape 2 of 5], November 10, 1986 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Curriculum Workshop: Mathematics for Computer Science," Second Day [Tape 3 of 5], November 11, 1986 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Curriculum Workshop: Mathematics for Computer Science," Second Day [Tape 4 of 5], November 10, 1986 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Curriculum Workshop: Mathematics for Computer Science," Third Day [Tape 4 of 5], November 10, 1986 (Box 65, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 1 of 10], June 17, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 2 of 10], June 17, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 3 of 10], June 18, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 4 of 10], June 18, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 5 of 10], June 19, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 6 of 10], June 19, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 7 of 10], June 20, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 8 of 10], June 20, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 9 of 10], June 21, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Technical Managers Advanced Workshops," Filmed by (IASIS) & (D.S.M.C) [Tape 10 of 10], June 21, 1991 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Understanding Defense Systems Acquisition Management (D.S.A.M)," Edited Version [Tape 1 of 1], December 17, 1986 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Understanding Defense Systems Acquisition Management (D.S.A.M)," Unedited Version [Tape 1 of 1], December 17, 1986 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Dr. John N. Warfield, in a Television Interview by Hillary Austin," Demosophia Room, George Mason University, February 26, 1986 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Dr. John N. Warfield, in a Television Informal Interview by Hillary Austin," Demosophia Room, George Mason University, March 20, 1986 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Wrap-up Comments of DARPA Users Group", July 17, 1987 (Box 66, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Applications in Industry & Government," Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #3 [A.N. Christakis, M. Van Hoose], October 5, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Undergraduate Education in United States," Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #4 [John N. Warfield], October 12, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "The Mathematics of Structure,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #6 [John N. Warfield], November 2, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "applications in Ghana, Liberia & Mexico,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #7 [John N. Warfield], November 9, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Higher Education & The Thought Leaders,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #8 [John N. Warfield], November 16, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "The Legacy of Charles Sanders Peirce,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #9 [John N. Warfield], November 23, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "The Work Program of Complexity,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #10 [John N. Warfield], November 30, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Applications of Interactive Management in Cyprus,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #11 [Benjamin J. Broome], December 7, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "The Wand-Waver Solution,"Johnson Center Complexity Lecture #12 [John N. Warfield], December 14, 1998 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Redesigning the National Marine FIsheries Services (N.M.F.S) for the 1990'S," Center for Interactive Management, 1986 (Box 67, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "American Institute for Interactive Management (A.I.I.M) Planning Sessions," [Tape 1 of 2], February 22, 1989 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "American Institute for Interactive Management (A.I.I.M) Planning Sessions," [Tape 2 OF 2], February 22, 1989 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Discovery & Complexity," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], January 30, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - Discovery & Complexity," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], January 30, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Resolving Complexity in Organizations,"Original Tape Seminar #4 [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], February 20, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Resolving Complexity in Organizations,"Original Tape Seminar #4 [John N. Warfield] [Tape 2 of 2], February 20, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Discovery & Complexity," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], February 6, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Discovery & Complexity," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 2 of 2], February 6, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Complexity Lectures," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], February 13, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Complexity Lectures," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 2 of 2], February 13, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Complexity Lectures," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 1], February 27, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Complexity Lectures," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 1], March 6, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Complexity Lectures," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 1], March 13, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Resolving Complexity in Organizations," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 of 2], March 20, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Resolving Complexity in Organizations," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 2 of 2], March 20, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Discovery & Complexity in Organizations," [John N. Warfield] [Tape 1 OF 2], April 3, 1999 (Box 68, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  - "Making Decision on Reducing Public Expenditures," Kent, Ohio City Council, 1978-1979 (Box 69, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "Toward A Balanced Budget: Making the Tough Decession Michigan, 1979-1980 (Box 69, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "Interview with Alexander N. Christakis, "John N. Warfield Theory Description, 1985-1986 (Box 69, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "Interview with Alexander N. Christakis, "John N. Warfield Theory Description, 1986 (Box 69, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Service (N.M.F.S)," [Tape 1 of 4], Center for Interactive Management, September 30, 1985 (Box 70, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Service (N.M.F.S)," [Tape 2 of 4], Center for Interactive Management, September 30, 1985 (Box 70, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Service (N.M.F.S)," [Tape 3 of 4], Center for Interactive Management, September 30, 1985 (Box 70, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Service (N.M.F.S)," [Tape 4 of 4], Center for Interactive Management, January 16,1986 (Box 70, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "Redesigning the National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S) for the 1990's "Center for Interactive Management, February 1986 (Box 71, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
  - "National Marine Fisheries Services (N.M.F.S)," Sessions, November 1985 (Box 71, Folder Videotape (3/4 inch))
- Series 3: Transparencies and Other Teaching Materials, 1979-2005; (27 boxes)
  - "Index to Transparencies & Transparencies Photocopies", 1985-1989 (Box 72)
  - "Reasoning Through Relationships," [Transparencies], undated (Box 72)
  - "Language," [Transparencies], 1988 (Box 72)
  - "Cultural Change Sequence," Analytical Powertrain Program Sequence Chart [Ford Motor Company], 1992 (Box 72)
  - "Iowa State University Press," Copyright Permissions, 1994 (Box 72)
  - "Encyclopedia of Superficial Intelligence" [Transparencies], undated (Box 72)
  - "George Friedman Project Interactions", 1995 (Box 72)
  - (IASIS) Videotape, Notes for Cataloging & Indexing", undated (Box 72)
  - "Complexity Lectures," Johnson Center Programs, 1998 (Box 73)
  - "Complexity Lecture Number 8," Johnson Center Lecture Series, 1998 (Box 73)
  - "Complexity Lecture Number 9," Johnson Center Lecture Series, 1998 (Box 73)
  - Johnson Center Lecture Series on Complexity," Completion Plan for Lectures 8,9, 10, 11 & 12 [John N. Warfield], 1998 (Box 73)
  - "Interactive Management Associates - Miscellaneous Interactions", 1998 (Box 73)
  - "Education," [Transparencies Relating to Higher Education, its Problems, and Ways to Improve it], 1992-1998 (Box 73)
  - "Organizations," [Transparencies Relating to Organizations, Their Problems, and Ways to Save Them When WOrking With Complexity], undated (Box 73)
  - "Formalism," [Transparencies], undated (Box 74)
  - "Processes," [Transparencies Relating to a Variety of Processes, Showing Examples of Many of the Types, Relating to Interactive Management], undated (Box 74)
  - "Models," [Model Types & Options Field], undated (Box 74)
  - "Sciences," [Transparencies] [1 of 2], undated (Box 74)
  - "Sciences," [Transparencies] [2 of 2], undated (Box 74)
  - "Generic Design Science & Interactive Management," Overview, Diagnostics [Transparencies], 1994 (Box 75)
  - "Human Beings," [Transparencies Relating to Human Behavior, Distinctions Among Individuals, Groups and Organizations], 1995 (Box 75)
  - "Thought Leaders," [Transparencies], undated (Box 75)
  - "Transparencies for the Wess Presentation", 1999 (Box 75)
  - "President Johnson's George Mason University Image Session Transparencies", 1985 (Box 75)
  - "Berlin Study Proposal," [Handouts & Transparencies], 1988 (Box 75)
  - National Technology Center - Vlannes Correspondence & Proposal," [Transparencies], 1986 (Box 75)
  - "Systems Engineering: Methodology for Large Scale Systems", 1989 (Box 75)
  - "Center for Interactive Management Applications - World Map," [Transparencies], 1989 (Box 75)
  - "Greiner's Organization Practices," [Transparencies], undated (Box 75)
  - "Problematique," [Transparencies], 1989 (Box 75)
  - old Interactive Management Execrative Briefings [Transparencies, 1984 (Box 75)
  - "Organizational Development," [Transparencies], undated (Box 75)
  - "John N. Warfield's Budapest Presentation," [Transparencies], undated (Box 75)
  - "An Example of Applying Options Field Methodology - Planning to go to the Movies," [Transparencies], undated (Box 75)
  - "Annotated Bibliography of Publications," [John N. Warfield], May 1989 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - "Annotated Bibliography of Publications," [John N. Warfield], December 1986 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - "Annotated Bibliography of Publications," [John N. Warfield], May 1988 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - "A Course in Generic Design - 1985 Version," (IASIS) (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - "A Course in Generic Design for Engineers- 1984 Version" (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - "A Users Guide to Public Systems Methodology," [Wila H. Thisen, Andrew P. Sage, John N. Warfield], July 2, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - "A Users Guide to Public Methodology: Draft User-Oriented Description of System Methods", 1981 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - "A Users Guide to Public Systems Methodology: Draft Algorithm Descriptions for Policy Advisers & Analysts", August 7, 1979 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - "A Users Guide to Public Systems Methodology: John N. Warfield's Letter to Wiley & Son's Publications", April 1981 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - "Proposal to National Science Foundation: A Users Guide to Public Methodology", undated (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - "Demosophia: A Specially Designed Situation Room", 1987 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - "Detractors to Effective System Design," [John N. Warfield], 1987 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - "Developing a Design Culture in Higher Education," [1987] (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - "Development of Generalized Design Theory & Methodology," [Christakis, Keever, Warfield], 1987 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - The Study of the Design Process: (N.S.F) Design Workshop", February 1987 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - "Dimensionality," [John N. Warfield], 1987 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - "Consensus Methodology Parameters," [John N. Warfield], December 29, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - "Consensus Methodologies: Extensions, Restrictions & Metrics," [John N. Warfield], undated (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - "Conceptual Science: Integrative Science", 1987 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - "A Complexity Metric for High-Level Software Languages", October 21, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - "Complementary Relations & Map Reading, Complete Inference Systems" [John N. Warfield], June 6, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - "Annotated Bibliography of Project Reports," [C.I.M), 1982-1987 (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - "An Example of an Options Field: To Design the Next Generation DARPA Information System", August 7, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - "Advances in Generic Design Science", 1987 (Box 76, Folder 24)
  - "2 + 2 = 5," [John N. Warfield], December 1987 (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - "Implicit Aspects of Much Systems Thinking," [John N. Warfield], 1988 (Box 76, Folder 26)
  - "Identification & Clarification of Roles & Responsibilities During & Following the Conduct of an Interactive Management Session", 1988 (Box 76, Folder 27)
  - "Gibbs," Study Notes on Book by M. Rukeyser, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - "Evaluation of Dr.Oichi's Algorithm for Transitive Bordering," [John N. Warfield], 1988 (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - "Editorial," Systems Research, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - "Do as I Say: A Review Essay of John W.Burton, Resolving Deep-Rooted Conflict: A Handbook," [John N. Warfield, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 31)
  - "Criteria for a Science of Design," [John N. Warfield], May 1988 (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - "Book Review: Systems & Control Encyclopedia,"Madan G.Singh, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - "What Disciplines Large-Scale Systems Design?", 1987 (Box 76, Folder 34)
  - "Triads in Thought & Action," [Draft], undated (Box 76, Folder 35)
  - "Transferability of the Interactive Management Systems for Planning & Generic Design Needs in the Department of Defense," Proposal, June 1987 (Box 76, Folder 36)
  - "Thinking About Systems,"an Editorial Written for Journal of Systems Research, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 37)
  - "Theory of Relations as the Foundation of Knowledge", April 4, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 38)
  - "A Reading of Bochenski's A History of Formal Logic", April 1987 (Box 76, Folder 39)
  - Philosophy Ignored: The Achilles Heel of the Software Industry," [John N. Warfield], 1986 (Box 76, Folder 40)
  - "Oversight & Steering for Effective System Design," [John N. Warfield, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 41)
  - "Notes on Strategic Defense Initiative," [John N. Warfield], November 28, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 42)
  - "Systems & Control Encyclopedia,"Madan G. Singh, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 43)
  - "Interpretive Structural Modeling," In the Encyclopedia of Systems & Control, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 44)
  - "Integrative Science,Interactive Management, Generic Design & Social Problem Solving," [John N. Warfield], October 22, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 45)
  - "Influences: Warfield Class & Seminar Lectures at C.I.M", 1986-1987 (Box 76, Folder 46)
  - "Implications of Scale for System Design," [John N. Warfield], 1987 (Box 76, Folder 47)
  - "Fundamentals of Complexity," Draft No.1, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 48)
  - "Domain of Science Model Extensions & Restrictions," [John N. Warfield], November 10, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 49)
  - Appendix, Two Classes of Management Problems, undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Outline for Developing Strategic and Operational Management Plans, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Talk and Presentation Materials of Dr. David Keever for CIM, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Talks with Dr. David Keever for CIM, 1984-1988, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Talks with Dr. David Keever for CIM: Catholic Charities, undated (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Talks and Presentations by Dr. David Keever: University/Industry Cooperation, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Results of Voting and Cases in CIM, undated (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - "Portraying the Complexities of Environmental Education and Strategies for Learning", undated (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Alexander Christakis, "Pathways to Peace", undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - AIIM Brochure for CIM: 1985, undated (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Talk and Presentation Material by Dr. David Keever for CIM: 1984-1985, undated (Box 77, Folder 11)